Saleem Shaik

Email: Saleem123 shaik@rediffmail.com

Mobile: +91 9676343090

Objective

To serve in an organization, which offers challenging opportunities and the work environment, where I can add value by contributing my experience, knowledge in achieving the company goals. Simultaneously, it would give me an opportunity for my career enhancement.

Academic Qualification

- Master of Computer Applications, Alagappa University, India, in 2011.
- Post Graduate Diploma in Computer Application, Alagappa University, India, in 2008.
- Bachelor in Commerce, Dr. B.R. Ambedkar Open University, India, in 2001.

Career History

Company: M/s Nader Al Zayer Trading Est.

Position: Sales Executive

Country: Dammam, Saudi Arabia Period: Jan 2016 To Jan 2018

➤ Company: M/s. Microhard Computers – Chip Level Servicing Centre

Position: System Administrator
Country: Kadapa, Andhra Pradesh
Period: Aug 2011 To Aug 2014

> Company: M/s. Kuwait India International Exchange Co.

Position: Hardware & Software Maintainer

Country: Kadapa, Andhra Pradesh Period: Dec 2001 To Aug 2003

Duties & Responsibilities

- Typing letters and filing documents
- Updating records using computer database and spreadsheet software
- Answering the telephone and dealing with enquiries
- Making appointments and keeping diaries
- Taking minutes at meetings, possibly using shorthand
- Dealing with incoming and outgoing post
- Drafting letters and other documents
- Photocopying and printing
- Good spoken and written communication skills
- Preparing and distributing papers and documents for meetings
- Maintaining accuracy and good attention to detail
- Replying to general correspondence
- Implementing new procedures and administrative systems
- Organizes work by reading and routing correspondence; collecting information; initiating telecommunications.
- Maintain customer confidence and protects operations by keeping information confidential.
- Liaising with relevant organizations.
- Maintain and manage all documents for project ensuring they are easily accessible and stored according to company requirements.
- Input information into required registers ensuring all information is accurate and up to date.
- Maintain registers of all receipts and issues or submissions of documents and correspondence.

Saleem-CV Page 1 of 2

Technical Support & IT Skills

- Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers and scanners.
- Connect and configure peripheral devices and insure compatibility.
- Install, repair and configure windows operating system & Microsoft office applications.
- Configuration of routers and switches.
- Troubleshoot and resolve software, hardware and network problems.
- Review and Troubleshoot Software and Hardware Problems.
- Planning and undertaking scheduled maintenance upgrades.
- Managing stocks of equipment, consumables and other supplies.
- Recording problems and their solutions for future reference.
- In depth knowledge of Microsoft Office suites and internet telephone operations.
- Confidence with IT and computer packages
- Excellent PC skills including Word, Access, Excel and PowerPoint
- Full knowledge of Microsoft Office programs & File Sharing and Document controller programs.
- Fully equipped with the knowledge of internet and internet browsing.

Certificates & Training Courses

- Office Automation, Certified Year (2012)
- Diploma in Computer Aided Drafting (MEP), Certified Year (2007)
- Auto CAD, 3D's Max, Micro station
- 2D Drafting, 3D Modeling, Animation, Walkthrough
- Diploma in MS-Office

Other Skills

- Energetic and capable of working independently and a good deal of autonomy.
- Have excellent time management skills & can meet the deadlines without compromising on quality.
- Excellent communication & interpersonal skills.
- Excellent organizational and time-management skills
- Confidence with a range of computer software
- The ability to work under pressure and meet deadlines
- Tact and discretion, for dealing with any confidential information

Personal Profile

Languages Known: Arabic, English, Hindi, Urdu, Telugu

Nationality: IndianMarital Status: Married

Children: Two

Saleem-CV Page 2 of 2